屏息
第一季第四集
幕雨字幕组译制
翻译：Brynt&超威闫叔  校订：Brynt&超威闫叔
时间轴：花格子神尼&拜仁小攀  后期：Brynt
你也换自行车骑了  安德伯雷医生
Aha. You've traded four wheels
for two, I see, Dr Enderbury.
实际上...
Actually...
“莫里斯”又拿修理厂修了
The Morris is at the garage again.
简单但可靠  对吧
Reliable simplicity, hm?
我觉得还是蛮有趣的
Quite enjoyable, I've found.
- 你骑了很远吗  - 没有
- Have you had to cycle far? - No.
我想差不多就九英里吧
Must be going on nine miles, I suppose.
嗯~
Hm.
- 鲍威尔府邸  - 你好
- The Powell residence.  - Hello.
我是特拉斯科特夫人  我想找鲍威尔夫人
Please may I speak with Mrs Powell?It's Mrs Truscott.
鲍威尔夫人刚刚出门了
Mrs Powell's just stepped out.
你能帮忙转告她我打电话过来
Please be so kind as to inform Mrs Powell
邀请她跟鲍威尔先生一起在周五共进晚餐吗
I telephoned to invite Mr and Mrs
Powell to dine here on Friday.
行  我肯定会帮你传达到的  再见
Yes.I'll be sure to give her the message.Goodbye.
早上好  医生
Good morning, Doctor.
我就是在会议前检查下器械而已
Just, you know, checking the
equipment before the meeting.
别告诉别人  好吗
Between us, eh?
当安德伯雷医生提醒我菲尔菲克斯小姐心率不稳时
I'd removed the polyp and completed
the dilatation and curettage
我正在移除鼻息肉  并进行扩张与刮除术
when Dr Enderbury alerted me that
Miss Fairfax's cardiac rhythm was erratic.
随即她就死亡了
She arrested moments after.
你估算过整个手术进行了多长时间吗
This procedure,Mr Powell,had lasted how long,do you estimate?
二十分钟
20 minutes.
你在暗示什么吗  教授
What are you suggesting, Professor?
会不会是安德伯雷医生对时间掌握的失误呢
A simple error of timing by Dr Enderbury?
人又孰能无过
We can all make mistakes.
但是我依然非常信任查理・安德伯雷
Although I would gladly entrust
my life to Charlie Enderbury.
他已经跟我共事了十五年
He's been my colleague for 15 years.
手术失误尽管可以理解  但也是灾难性的
A procedural error - though
understandable,but catastrophic.
要是有失误的话也都是我的
If there was any error, it was mine.
这不是我暗示你的意思
That is not what I am suggesting.
我当然知道你在暗示什么
I know exactly what you're suggesting.
莉莉  你来这儿有事吗
Lily? What are you doing here?
没事儿
Oh, nothing.
其实我是听说了菲尔菲克斯小姐的悲剧
Actually, it's this sad Miss Fairfax inquiry thingy.
但安德伯雷医生一向对这些事非常严谨的
Dr Enderbury takes these things very seriously.
这只是我的愚见
Well, that's what I see.
我一直觉得他是这一带最无畏的医生了
I expect he's the unflinching doctor
around this neck of the woods.
- 所以才导致他现在还依然膝下无子吗 - 天呐 不是的
- So no patter of tiny feet yet, then? - Gosh, no.
安德伯雷最不希望我挺个大肚子还整天哭哭啼啼
Last thing Dr Enderbury needs
is me moaning and swelling up and...
那他最近如何
And how is he?
工作不努力吗
Not working too hard?
你最清楚他们的为人了
You know what they're like.
我是说跟鲍威尔一起做的工作
With Mr Powell, I mean.
我想这件事我丈夫自有主张  护士长
Oh, my husband is very much his own man, Matron.
他现在在会议室  你可去那儿找到他
You'll find him in the conference room.
- 他们还冷静吗  - 说实话  一点也不
- Certainly took their time? - No, honestly.
我们俩一起进去的几率很小
It's rare we get in the room together.
莉莉
Lily.
我有事正好经过这儿  就想着来看看你们
I was doing my errands and thought I'd pop in.
对了  特拉斯科特夫妇想知道
Oh,and Mr and Mrs Truscott wondered
我们周五晚上有没有空一起吃个饭
if we were free for supper Friday evening.
慢慢说不着急  莉莉
Well, one thing at a time, Lily.
莉莉  你今天早上看起来非常动人
Lily, you look enchanting this morning.
你觉得呢  查理
Don't you think, Charlie?
说真的  你真不该过来的
Really, you shouldn't have come.
不  你说得对
No. You are right.
我只想告诉你我有多爱你
I wanted you to know just how much I love you.
安德伯雷医生
Dr Enderbury?
你不介意的话请进来吧
If you don't mind.
在这场悲剧之后  我检查了器械
And, naturally,after the tragedy,
I checked both the equipment...
还反思了整个手术过程
and our procedures.
而且你今天早上又检查过一遍器械对吗
And again this morning you checked the equipment?
一只小鸟告诉我的  你没检查过吗
A little birdy told me. No?
要是我们排除技术故障的话
So, if we rule out a technical malfunction,
就只有鲍威尔先生所说的人为失误这个可能了
we are left with,as Mr Powell
suggested, a human error.
也可能是病人肺部血栓  也可能是其他自然因素
Or a pulmonary embolism or some other natural cause
你现在有过度焦虑吗
Were you under any undue anxiety?
梅塔
Mehta?
有传言说安德伯雷医生协助
Rumour has it that Dr Enderbury had been
鲍威尔医生接收了一名私诊病人
assisting Mr Powell with a private patient.
没有
No.
这刚好发生在菲尔菲克斯小姐去世的前一天晚上
The very night before the unfortunate Miss Fairfax passed away.
而且沃斯伯护士长也告诉过我警察也提及过...
And Matron Vosper tells me that the police had mentioned -
那个啊  对  确实是有个急诊
Oh, that. Yes. The emergency admission.
但没在这间医院
It wasn't here, though.
- 那在哪儿  - 一栋居民楼中
- So where? - At a house.
但是从未有什么事发生
Uh, but nothing happened.
我能问你到底什么样的私人手术
Can I ask what private procedure required an
需要在私人住所进行  而且还需要麻醉师随同吗
anaesthetist at night, at a private residence?
我从未见过你这般的尤物
I have never seen anything as beautiful.
我从未要求过你进入我的生活  我有吗  鲍威尔夫人
I didn't ask you into my life,did I,Mrs Powell?
我从没想过...
I never expected...
- 但那些事...  - 不行
- But things... - No.
检察长
Inspector.
不能在这儿做
Not like this.
我会通知你时间地点的
I will tell you when and where.
现在  请你先下车
Now get out of the car.
- 对了  - 什么事  修女
- Right... - Yes, Sister?
我有个工作交给你
I have a job for you.
黎明就出发
Leaving at dawn.
鲍威尔先生需要一个护士跟他去多塞特
Mr Powell needs a nurse to assist
him with a multiple delivery,
进行一个多胎孕妇分娩手术  他专门让我来问问你
in Dorset, and he asked for you specifically.
要我是你的话  我会忘记我刚才说的话
If I was you, I'd forget I ever even told
直接回家好好睡上一觉
you and go home and get a good night's sleep.
- 听懂了吗  - 懂了
- You hear me? - I do.
- 然后呢  - 我会忘记你刚才说的话
- And? - I've forgotten you ever told me.
嗯~嗯~
Mm-hm.
伊丽莎白  黑灯瞎火的坐这儿干嘛呢
Elizabeth. What are you doing sitting in the dark?
我想可能是刚才想事情入迷了  不知不觉太阳就落山了
I...suppose I was lost in thought and the sun set.
今天忙吗
Busy day?
J太太给你留了些东西
Mrs J left you something.
- 晚安  奥托  - 我早上要出发去看诊
- Good night, Otto. - I'm off in the morning.
今晚我就得出门
I'll be away for the night.
就停在这儿行了  零就不用找了
Just here, please. Keep the change.
早安
Morning.
你想干什么  瑞奇
What do you want, Richie?
对我来说现在可还是半夜呢
It's the middle of the night for me.
你看起来过得不好啊  亲爱的
You look rough, darling.
我昨晚整晚都没睡
I've been up all night.
是因为一个急诊
It was an emergency.
给一个病入膏肓的病人治疗
Treating a patient that was desperately ill.
那却让我想你了
It made me want you.
天呐  真浪漫呢
Christ, how romantic.
但是我意识到我是爱你的
But I realise I love you.
你不必爱我的
You don't have to love me, you know.
我发誓我真的爱你
I swear I do.
听着...
Look...
听我说
Listen.
这里发生的任何事都与爱情无关  好吗
What happens here has got nothing
to do with love.All right?
你把你的爱都留给你那美丽动人的简吧  瑞奇
You save that love for your beautiful Jean, Richie.
在这儿发生的...
What happens here...
一切都只是为了取乐而已
...is simply to do with pleasure.
你懂吗
Do you understand?
鲍威尔先生  早上好  先生
Mr Powell. Good morning, sir.
有传言说你要去多塞特为
Rumour is you're off to Dorset for a
一名有先兆子痫多胞胎孕妇进行分娩手术
multiple delivery with pre-eclampsia.
要是我能亲眼见证您的工作的话  我情愿
I would give my left leg to witness you
把我的左腿都奉献给你  要是我能帮上忙的话...
at work and if I could be of any use...
抱歉  总有一天我会成为科恩医生
Sorry. One day I will be Dr Cohen but
但现在叫我山姆也无所谓
right now I'm more comfortable with Sam.
山姆  我恐怕我真的要...
Sam. I'm afraid I really uh...
我实在是想不出有什么理由不带你去
I actually cannot think of an excuse not to take you.
- 我一定会成为你的左膀右臂的  - 好吧
- I will be indispensible. - Right.
- 我本来可以做更好的决定的  - 你好  护士
- Rather against my better judgment...- Hello,Nurse
我叫科恩
Cohen.
- 但我...  - 你要是叫他山姆的话他会更乐意的
- But I am - He is more comfortable as Sam
而且他现在可是我的得力助手
and he is indispensible, Nurse Wilson.
是吗  鲍威尔先生
Is he, Mr Powell?
希望我没有打扰到你们
Well,I certainly hope I'm not the gooseberry.
鲍威尔夫人  我没迟到吧
Mrs Powell? I'm not late?
当然没有  但我们现在得说话小点声
Heavens,no!But do let's keep our voices down.
托马斯还在睡着呢
Thomas is still asleep.
鲍威尔先生昨晚也因为
Mr Powell announced late last night
一项仁慈的任务很晚才回来
he'd been summoned on a mercy mission,
所以我觉得现在也许是把托马斯
so I thought this might be a good few
介绍给你父母的最好时机
days to introduce him to your parents.
去塞尔西小小地渡个假
In Selsey. A little holiday.
我们...现在是在说期中假的事儿吗
We uh...talked about half term.
你不觉得他那个不太好的胸腔
The sea air will clear that nasty chest
呼吸点海边的空气会更好点吗
he seems to have acquired, don't you think?
- 但他还要上课  - 我会跟学校那边说的
- But he has school.- I'll telephone the secretary
现在有辆去维多利亚的大巴
There's a coach up to Victoria and
跟一辆去奇切斯特的火车
then, I imagine, a train up to Chichester.
你可以给我带些石头回来做纪念
You could bring me back some rock.
特拉斯科特  你有看到奥托在哪儿吗  老兄
Truscott, have you seen Otto anywhere, old man?
鲍威尔先生啊  据我所知  现在在多塞特呢
Mr Powell, I understand, is in Dorset.
帮一个有并发症的多胞胎孕妇接生
A multiple births with complications.
好吧  我忘了这茬了
Ah, that's right.Completely slipped my mind.
现在没人可以帮你了  查理
No-one to hold your hand, Charlie?
国王已死  国王万岁
The King is dead! Long live the King!
你不能让亨明斯跟一个神志不清的女孩
You can't leave Hemmings alone with an unconscious girl
在没人看管情况下单独待一起  吉妮
without there being a... Jeannie!
你在这儿呢  还真是无处不在啊
Here you are. Been everywhere.
我想告诉你我们周五晚上有安排了
I wanted to tell you we've having the Friday evening do.
你先去吧
Ah, there's a good chap.
你在这儿来干什么呢
Look, what are you doing here?
来看看你为什么没有回家
Seeing as you didn't come home...
我们一晚上都在忙呢
We were rushed off our feet all night.
我觉得还是亲自来告诉你更好
...I thought it'd be better if I came
here to tell you myself.
我已经邀请了泰姬陵夫妇
I've invited Dr and Mrs Taj Mahal...
鲍威尔夫妇  以及查理和莉莉
..the Powells...Charlie and Lily.
我可以做得来  我可以
I can do it. I can.
还有你父母亲
And your mother and father.
但是  吉妮  你不会做饭  而且我母亲...
But, Jeannie, you can't cook and my mother -
莉莉答应帮忙的  好吧  不仅仅是帮忙
Lily's promised to help. Well, more  than help.
但这不是重点  好吗
But that's not the point, is it?
你不是一直想这样吗
I thought this was what you wanted.
管他呢  所有人都很乐意来做客
Anyway, everyone said they'd be delighted.
晚上八点  别迟到了
Eight. Don't be late.
- 你睡着了  - 夜晚真短啊
- You slept. - Short night.
立正
Atten-tion.
你好  我是杰克逊  你一定就是鲍威尔了
Hello. Jackson. You must be Powell.
我们已经给你在护士房里整理了一张床
We've cleared you a bed at the nurses' cottage.
我们是同一个团队的  修女  而且很时髦的
We're a team, Sister. Very modern.
我们已经在公牛头宾馆订好了三间房
And we have booked three rooms at the Bull's Head
- 我们能先见见我们的病人吗  - 您先请
- Shall we visit our patient? - Ah. After you.
哦~  你看起来真像是最英勇的士兵
Oh,don't you look every bit the brave soldier!
你会过得非常愉快的  不是吗
You'll have a marvellous time,won't you?
难道他不会吗
Won't he?
出租车来了
That'll be the taxi.
好了  托马斯  我希望你能特别留意
Now,Thomas dear.I want you to take particular
J太太  别把她在火车上
care of Mrs J and not leave her on the train
或是在维多利亚给弄丢了
or lose her at Victoria.
- 好了  快走吧  - 走吧
- For heaven's sake, go. - Come on.
拜  宝贝
Bye, darling.
拜
Bye.
先天性惊厥血毒症  鲍威尔先生  以及三个似胎心脏
Pre-eclamptic toxaemia,Mr Powell,and three foetal hearts.
谢谢  杰克逊医生
Thank you, Dr Jackson.
是执事小姐  先生
Miss Deacon, sir.
呃...
Uh...
早上好  小姐
Good morning, young lady.
夫人
Madam.
我是收养机构的 鲍威尔先生 我还是待在屋里的好
Adoption services,Mr Powell,and I
would rather stay in the room,sir.
要是您不要要的话就请便吧  夫人  好了 小姐
If you must, madam.Now,Miss.
请接通穆里根检察长
Yes.Chief Inspector Mulligan,please.
我是穆里根检察长
Chief Inspector Mulligan speaking.
喂  检察长  你可以晚上八点来我家
Hello,Inspector.You can come
to the house at eight o'clock.
请带上陈词跟照片
And bring the statements and the photographs,please.
我会准时到的
I'll be there.
你要喝点什么吗  先生
What's your poison, sir?
- 苹果汁  - 呃...
- Apple juice. - Ah.
- 你呢  威尔森护士  - 杜松子酒跟奎宁水
- Nurse Wilson? - Gin and tonic.
- 你不必说出口  - 我觉得我有必要说
- You don't need to say it. - Oh,I think I do.
我们开了六个小时的车
Have we really driven for six hours
到这里来就是为了让这些婴儿
to deliver babies that are going to  be taken
一出娘胎就被迫与母亲分离吗
from their mother the moment open the womb?
不  我们开车六个小时来是为了确保
No. We've driven for six hours
执事小姐的孩子不受到任何伤害地出生
to ensure that neither Miss Deacon
or her babies come to any harm.
当然很显然不只是这样
And it isn't just that.
干嘛
What?
为什么我要让你来
Why I asked you.
我恐怕越过了最黑暗的地方  鲍威尔先生
I've gone over to the dark side,I'm afraid,Mr Powell.
这个社工可能是纳粹秘密警察
That social worker might have been the Gestapo.
我们是医学工作者
We are medics.
但这并不意味着我们就不能阻止坏事的发生
It doesn't mean we can't stop terrible things happening.
不  但这意味着我们的判断必须在我们的能力范围之内
No,but it does mean that our judgments
are based on things we can influence,
而不是我们所希望或是所感觉到的而已
rather than things we might hope or feel.
这真是...
That is so...
干杯  不管怎样
Cheers...anyway,
非常感谢你先生  能让我加入你们这个
and thank you, sir, for allowing me to join
you on what has become a nightmare story
婴儿从生母怀里被抢夺的恐怖故事里面来
of babies being ripped from their mother's bosom.
敬已成定局的事
To moral certainty.
他不是那个意思  对吧  山姆
He didn't mean that. Did you, Sam?
对  不是那个意思
Yes and no.
不管怎样  我的头现在要被应承专业自杀
However, at this moment I am torn
between committing professional suicide
跟去厕所这两件事快给撕成两半了
or going to the toilet.
我没打算带个陪护过来的
I didn't actually intend to bring a chaperone.
- 他确实让人难以拒绝  - 如果你喜欢小家伙的话
- He's sort of irresistible. - If you like puppies.
他们自由所属
They have their place.
我现在累坏了  我得去躺会儿了
But I am exhausted...and off to bed.
- 早点睡  - 威尔森护士
- Early night. - Nurse Wilson...
有事吗  鲍威尔先生
Yes, Mr Powell?
祝你睡个好觉
Sleep well.
我刚刚说了什么吗  我觉得我刚刚一直在
What did I say?I thought I was walking the line
敏感跟有魅力两者之间游刃有余啊
between "charm" and "sensitive" effortlessly.
不是你的缘故
It's not you.
她只是累了
She's tired.
要是你问我她怎么样的话
Well, she is absolute bloody dynamite,
她肯定是个极为优秀的人
if you ask me,Mr Powell.
我或许不该带她过来的
I probably shouldn't have brought her.
我不清楚啦  先生
Oh, I don't know.Sir.
你不喝酒吗  还是说只是今晚不喝
Don't drink?Or just not tonight?
要是您不介意我这么问的话
If you don't mind me asking.
好奇的脑袋知道什么该问什么不该问的  科恩
An enquiring mind should know its limits, Cohen.
要是我问的太多的话  我向你道歉  先生
Sorry, sir, if I'm too forward.
我之所以不喝酒  是因为在酒精作用下
I don't drink because I once,under the influence,
可能会导致我犯非常严重的错误
made a terrible mistake.
- 干杯  - 干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
查理
Charlie.
伊丽莎白  抱歉  我本来想给你打电话来着  但...
Elizabeth.I'm sorry.I was going to telephone but...
呃...奥托不在家
Uh... Otto's not here.
这个我知道  这就是我为什么...
No, I know. That's why I...
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
想喝点什么吗  查理
Can I get you something, Charlie?
不  不用了  谢谢  我...
No. No, thank you. I...
一切都还好吗  伊丽莎白
Is everything all right, Elizabeth?
当然  我只是很惊讶而已  我没想到现在会有人造访
Yes.I...just was surprised.I wasn't expecting anyone.
汤米呢
Where's Tommy?
J太太想回去探望她的母亲
Um... Mrs J wanted to see her mother.
而托马斯胸腔不是很好  所以他们现在去了塞尔西
He had a nasty chest, so they're in Selsey.
他们可能要旅行几天才能回
They thought they'd make a trip of it for a few days.
所以我现在才一个人在家
And so I'm here...alone,
奥托接生小孩去了
Otto delivering babies.
对
Yes.
你能给我来呗威士忌苏打...
You know, a whisky soda would...
马上就来
Coming right up.
事实上  我正是想跟你谈谈奥托来着
Actually, it was in fact Otto I wanted to talk to you about.
干杯
Chin-chin.
你知道的...嗯...
You see...um...
我现在来访可能有点冒犯了
...I could be in a touch of bother.
你知道的  我现在很担心  而且我现在非常依赖奥托
Oh,you know,I do worry and I do absolutely rely on Otto.
你真的还好吗  伊丽莎白
Are you sure you're all right,Elizabeth?
你这话什么意思
Whatever do you mean?
你看起来...有点心不在焉
You seem... Well, distracted.
天呐  哪有的事
Good heavens, no.
要不是奥托对我的“恩惠”
I wouldn't be in this mess
我现在也不会落得如此下场
if it wasn't for Otto and his specials.
你知道吗  亲爱的伊丽莎白
And do you know, dear Elizabeth,
要是一个警察突然来到这里的话
if a police inspector was to walk in here right now,
我真不知道我会不会
I'm not sure I wouldn't just put
举起双手说道：“我有罪 清逮捕我吧”
my hands up and say "guilty as charged".
我真非常害怕终有一天他会弃我于不顾
I'm afraid that one day he is going
to leave me hanging in the wind.
- 奥托视你为兄长   - 我可不这么想
- Otto cares for you like a brother. - I don't think so.
我不认为奥托除了自己之外还会关心任何人
I don't think Otto cares for anyone but himself.
查理  你这样说真是太过分了
Charlie,that's a terrible thing to say.
我能感觉到现在命悬一线
I can feel the noose tightening.
奥托应该知道  要是他不仁
Otto should know, from me...
我也会不义  我绝不会对发生在塞浦路斯
I will not keep silent about what happened
关于你们俩的事只字不提
in Cyprus about him and you.
我会一直身怀歉意  伊丽莎白
I'm sorry, Elizabeth, for ever.
- 要是我...  - 查理
- If...I - Charlie.
我们骗了他
We lied for him.
我双手沾满过鲜血  而且我依然在撒谎  你也一样
I had blood on my hands and I am lying still.You are too.
查理
Charlie...
不管是你还是我  奥托都不会让我们失望的
Otto will never let you down, or me.
我知道他不会的
I know that.
而且你对我们而言  是一位非常特别的朋友
Besides, you are a very special friend.
对
Yes.
有没有可能一个可怜的女人因自然因素死亡呢
Could be that...poor woman died of natural causes.
而非失误
No fault.
可能是吧
Could be.
安德伯雷要是刚才来这儿干嘛呢
What was Dr Enderbury doing here just now?
他没通知一声就过来了  检察长
He arrived unannounced, Inspector.
别  伊丽莎白
Please, Elizabeth...
你没必要跟我撒谎
...there is no reason to lie to me.
我没有
I'm not.
你现在能给我你掌握的陈词跟照片吗
Now, would you please give me the
statements and the photographs you have?
你是如此绝世倾城
You are so beautiful.
我可是花重金才买到的
I asked for the best money could buy.
那个年轻的售货员还笑着说
Young lady laughed and said,
“这肯定是送给一位非常特别之人”
"It must be for someone very special."
- 我要你的陈词  - 当然
- I need the statements. - Of course.
我不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you.
- 你最好现在离开这儿  检察长  - 请叫我罗纳尔德
- You'd better go, Inspector. - Ronald. Please.
你的倩影在我的脑海里挥之不去
You've been in my head...
让我为之疯狂
..driving me wild...
彻夜难眠  脑子里想的全是你
I've not slept, thinking about you.
想着我们在一起的样子
Imagining us together.
但是后来...
But then to...
我们完得如此之快
..so quickly.
- 对不起  - 别再说了
- I'm sorry. - Please...
我已经给了你想要的  现在快给我陈词跟照片
I've done what you wanted, now just give
me the statements and the photographs.
那我成了什么
What have I become?
我的一部分...
There's a part of me...
我的一部分消失不见了
There's a...part of me that's missing.
我的儿子死了  而且...
My son died and...
我一直在寻找
I've been looking,
寻找能填补这份空缺的东西
searching to fill that part...
但绝不是这样的
..not like this.
不
No...
我要的不是这样
Not like this.
没事了  罗纳尔德
It's all right...Ronald.
你只需要给我你掌握的东西
Just give me what you have...And...
我没有带来
I didn't bring them.
我以为你只是在戏弄我而已
I was convinced you were trying to trick me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
天呐  哦~  天呐
Oh, God! Oh, God!
- 妈咪  - 宝贝
- Mummy! - Darling.
我一直在求J太太早点带我回来  因为我不在他身边
I absolutely begged Mrs J to come
back early because I left him.
我想他肯定也想你想他一样想你
Well, I suspect he missed you
just as much as you missed him.
这个孩子看起来真像我爸爸
This one looks just like my da.
他很强壮
He's strong.
就跟我爸爸一样
Like my da.
啊  你来了
Ah, there you are.
我刚准备去找你呢  我们能出去谈谈吗
I was just on my way. Shall we?
我们很幸运看到爱丽斯还活着 还有三个健康的孩子
We're lucky that Alice is alive
and has three healthy babies.
我们跟你们伦敦人不一样  医生
We are not like you people from London,Doctor.
一个未婚先孕的孩子只会是一种情况
A child conceived out of wedlock is one thing.
她的父亲强奸了她
Her father forced himself on her.
他是这三个孩子的父亲
He is the father of those children.
而且执事小姐还是个未成年人
And Miss Deacon is a minor.
是的  鲍威尔先生
Yes, Mr Powell.
当她求助于我们时  我们会照顾他们跟爱丽斯
We will care for them and Alice when she turns to us.
非常感谢你为她所做的事
Thank you for what you've done.
看着这些婴儿被移送...
Seeing those babies being delivered...
你帮助爱丽斯的这种方式
the way you helped Alice...
让我感觉到从未有过的这般有活力
I don't think I've ever felt more alive...
这般开心
..or happier.
然后被告知他们...
And then to be told they were...
你有没有觉得生活总是爱跟你开玩笑
Do you think life is always like this
- playing tricks on you?
我觉得...
I think...
说真的吗
Truthfully?
我觉得只有今天
I think there's only ever today.
现在这一刻
Now.
我希望
I wish...
?给自己行个方便
?Do yourself a favour
?来段混音
?Have a Medley
我希望这算得上医学级
Medical grade, I'm hoping.
缺氧所有这些东西的根本路径
Lack of oxygen is,of course,the route of all this.
如果病人...
If a patient...
安德伯雷医生  好消息
Ah, Dr Enderbury, good news.
自然原因致死  就跟我们预料的一样
Natural causes. As we always thought.
菲尔菲克斯小姐死于自然因素
Miss Fairfax died of natural causes.
很明显大脑供氧不足的危险...
Obviously the danger with cerebral hypoxia...
我回来了  亲爱的
I'm home, dearest.
我们还有足够的时间送你去特拉斯科特家
We want ample time to get you to the Truscotts'.
你今天回来的比以前早  亲爱的
You're early, darling.
我知道吉妮就指望着你帮忙呢  还有啊  莉莉
I know how Jeannie's relying on you.Something else,Lil.
还有件事我要告诉你
Something else.
我没有失误
I didn't make a mistake.
- 我很确定你没有  - 但是  事实证明我真没有
- No. I was sure. - But, you see, I wasn't.
我知道我所做的事正一点一点将我给吞噬
I know what I am doing and all this has been eating me up.
可是为什么呢
For what reason?
莉莉
Lily?
谢谢
Thank you.
晚安
Good night.
我一直努力控制自己的情感  但我就是做不到
All I want to do is stop feeling
what I'm feeling, but I can't,
我真的不知道接下来该如何是好
and I do not know what to do any more.
我只是想待在你身边  仅此而已
I just want to be near you, nothing more.
- 晚安  - 晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
你觉得我跟那个护士有...戏吗  先生
That nurse.Do you think...me and her?Sir?
谁知道呢  是吧
Well, you never know, do you?
你想打给你的丈夫吗  道尔顿太太
Would you like to telephone
your husband, Mrs Dalton?
我一直觉得婚姻是我人生的枷锁  鲍威尔医生
I always found marriage rather too
ball-and-chain for my taste,Dr Powell.
那你结婚了吗
Is there anyone?
我开着一家餐馆跟夜总会  你觉得呢
I run a restaurant and a night club.What do you think?
那情况严重吗？
So, it's that serious?
如果能再做个活细胞组织检查的话我就能知道更多
The tests - the biopsy - should tell me more.
当然
Yes.
我一直都“活在当下”
Well, I always argued "live for the moment".
我想我一直都是个傻瓜
I suppose I've been a fool.
你一个月之前就该来找我的
You should have come to see me months ago.
- 这些症状… - 对  正如我所说…
- The symptoms - Yeah，like I said, I...
你要怎么跟理查德・特拉斯科特说
What are you going to say to Richard Truscott?
你到底怎么知道这些事的
How on earth do you know about that?
就在晚宴上他把你介绍给我们的那一刻
The moment he introduced us at dinner.
你不必独自面对
You don't have to face this alone.
我真不知道该如何是好
I'm not entirely sure what I'm going to do.
几点了
What time is it?
- 已经晚了  - 那简怎么办
- Late.- Well, what about Jean?
莉儿  你到底跑哪去了
Oh, Lil. Where the sodding heck are you?
来了  莉儿
Coming, Lil!
我知道我们来早了  但穿成这样
I know we are early but one cannot
make sense of the London Underground
我们不好意思在伦敦的大街上多待
and we could hardly walk the streets dressed like this.
这是我贤内  梅塔教授
This is my good wife, Professor Mehta,
但我们通常都称她为帕特丽夏
but we mere mortals are sometimes
allowed to call her Patricia.
快请进
Please, do come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
喝酒吗  我给你们…
Drink? What can I...?
呃  特拉斯科特医生呢
Oh, where is Dr Truscott?
他还沉浸在他的工作中  杜松子酒如何
Oh,he's just obsessed by his patients,
working every hour. God...Gin?
晚上好
Good evening.
天呐  我真想死你了
My God, I want you so badly. I really do.
- 我都在楼下滑了一跤  - 你已经家有贤妻了
- I slipped in downstairs. - You've got a perfectly good wife.
- 难道鱼与熊掌不能兼得吗  - 你真坏
- Can't I have both of you? - You are monstrous.
别  不行  理查德   真不行  别这样
No, Richard. No. No. Seriously.
若五年之后我们皆在人世  到了那时我们再见吧
If we're all still alive in five years,let's meet again.
别动真感情
As adults.
我们只是为了取乐而已
Just for pleasure.
我们真是幸运
We are ever so lucky.
遇到了理查德的父母这么慷慨的人
Richard's parents were frightfully generous.
他真是有福气
He was in oil.
他去过印度  也许你见过他
He went to India. Maybe you met him.
哦  这一定是莉儿了
Oh. That'll be Lil.
我去开吧
I'll go.
那…教授在哪高就
So...a professor? Of...?
伦敦大学   国际关系学
International affairs. University Of London.
天呐  你一定聪明绝顶
Gosh almighty. You must be an absolute brainbox.
- 杜松子酒加奎宁  谢谢  - 简
- Gin and tonic, please. - Jean.
亲爱的
Dearest.
托马斯在塞尔西的时候十分焦虑
Thomas got very anxious in Selsey.
孩子总在担心些事儿
Children worry at things.
我所做的一切都是为了托马斯
Everything-and I mean everything I do-is for Thomas,
仅仅是为了他
and Thomas alone.
别再问了  J太太
Please, Mrs J.
现在…
Now...
我再不走就迟到了
I shouldn't be late.
而且我现在不确定鲍威尔现在是会准时去那里
And I'm not at all sure whether Mr
Powell will be back in time to join me
还是会直接回家
or whether he'll come straight home.
好了  交给我吧
Right. Let's take a look.
简  你焖了多久
Jean, when did you put this in?
没多久啊  就刚刚
Just now, a second ago.
她醒来的第一句话就问“我的手镯呢”
The first thing she said was,"Where's my bracelet?"
“医生 我的手镯呢”整个手术室的人都说
"Doctor,where's my bracelet?"All the theatre could
“幸亏你没丢到别的地方”
say was, "Luckily,not where you left it."
这真搞笑
That's really quite funny.
谢谢 干了
Thank you. Boom-boom.
- 我的儿啊  - 哈
- Dearest. - Ah.
真是辛苦了
You're working too hard.
你不觉得你母亲过誉了吗  特拉斯科特医生
Are you feeling guilty, Dr Truscott?
嗯
Mm.
- 这是给你的亲爱的  - 你去哪了 回来这么晚
- Ah. These are for you, darling.
- Where have you been? You're late.
你今早答应我不会迟到  你答应过我跟我讲真话
You promised me this morning you wouldn't be late.
You promised you would tell me the truth.
梅塔教授  你认识强尼・唐科沃斯吗
Professor Mehta, do you know Johnny Dankworth?
现在才刚刚八点啊  我还不得去花店买花吗
It's eight o'clock.I had to go to the florist.
真是场盛宴啊
What a spread.
这个真好吃  简
This is delicious, Jean.
你应该告诉他们我们是素食主义者
You should have said we were vegetarians.
你看起来气色不错  安德伯雷太太  有什么好事吗
You look quite transformed, Mrs
Enderbury. Something changed?
没有啊  你想说什么呢
No. Whatever do you mean?
大家干杯
Cheers, everyone.
我不知道酒还够不够了
I wonder if we haven't had enough.
够了  母亲
Now, Mother...
- 你想说什么 亲爱的
- Whatever do you mean, dearest?
- 你就让简喝吧
- Let Jeannie be.
你说了算
Whatever you say.
- 非常荣幸见到你们
- It's been a delight to meet you.
- 你也不必走啊  母亲
- You don't have to go, Mother.
可是很明显我们在这不受欢迎
But we're clearly not welcome here.
你们当然受欢迎
Of course you are.
特拉斯科特 过来
Mr Truscott.
鲍威尔夫人 也很荣幸见到你
Mrs Powell, it's always a pleasure.
求你们别走
Please don't go.
邀请你们大家一起对我意义重大
It meant everything to me,
inviting you and everyone,
而且 我…
and I...
我知道我不该喝酒
I should have known not to drink.
不应该去做红酒烩牛肉
Not to try and cook...boeuf sodding bourguignon.
就算是莉儿帮忙我也不…
Even with Lil I can't...
我知道我一直都很让你失望  特拉斯科特太太
I know I've always been, and always
will be,a disappointment to you,Mrs Truscott.
- 我真的做不出什么能让您满意的事  - 吉妮
- There's nothing I can do about that.- Jeannie.
不 瑞奇
No, Richie.
你爱干嘛干嘛去  那从那儿回来就去哪儿去
Do what you want.Go back to wherever it is you go.
之前干嘛现在还干嘛去
Keep doing whatever it is you're doing.
我爱你  但我不能没有…
I love you but I can't live without...
你的爱
love.
顺便提一句  我看到圣奥尔本斯玛丽女王
Oh,by the way,I see they're advertising
for a new Head Of Department
召厅长的广告
at Queen Mary's in St Albans.
我觉得我可以去碰碰运气
Thought I might try my luck.
嗯
Mm.
你觉得如何
What do you say?
你当然不能永远活在鲍威尔的影子下
Well, you certainly can't be
in Mr Powell's shadow for ever,
肯定的
that's a definite.
准备好走了吗  亲爱的
Are you ready, dear?
我们也该走了
Shall we?
再见 安德伯雷太太
Mrs Enderbury.
待在房里别出来
Stay there.
吉妮
Jeannie?
我不能再装下去了
I can't pretend to be someone I'm not.
我觉得理查德对我连装都不想装一下了
And Richard can't pretend to care for me,I suppose.
他就这样的人
I think he does, you know.
- 你就尽说哄我开心的话吧  - 没有
- You're just saying what I want to hear.- No.
因为他不知道该如何想你表达他的情感
Because...he doesn't know
how to show you what he feels.
但那个女人
But that woman.
我怀疑你丈夫在隐瞒他的真实情感
I suspect there's a lot of your husband
pretending not to feel what he really feels.
- J太太  - 鲍威尔夫人呢
- Mrs J - Where's Mrs Powell?
她说她什么时候回来
When did she say she'd be home?
十一点  她去特拉斯科特家赴宴去了
At eleven.She was dining with Mr and Mrs Truscott.
但… 现在都已经午夜了
It's...after midnight.
她肯定已经在路上了
I'm sure she's on her way.
或许派对比他们预想的更尽兴
Perhaps the party was more fun
than we might imagine.
好吧  晚安吧  你先回去  我来等
Well, good night. Go home. I'll wait up.
快把陈词和照片交给我
Let me have the statements and the photographs.
求你了
Please.
你答应过的
You promised.
- 但我要给了你的话我就会失去你  - 求求你了
- But I'll lose you if I give them to you.- Please.
我会失去你的  伊丽莎白
I'll lose you, Elizabeth.
谢谢观看  更多字幕请关注“幕雨字幕组”新浪微博